A Guide to the Henry Miller Letters, 1964-1966
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Henry Miller Letters, 1964-1966
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8367
This collection consists of 10 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence, 1964-1966, between Henry Miller, Pacific Palisades, Calif., and William H. Runge, Charlottesville, Va., concerns Miller's gift to the University of Virginia Library of six watercolors and a copy of "Into the Night Life."
Contents List
- Henry Miller, Pacific Palisades, California, to William H. Runge, University of Virginia Library 1965 Oct 18, 1 page, TLS
  Offering a donation of a few of his water colors
- Henry Miller, Pacific Palisades, California, to William H. Runge, University of Virginia Library 1965 Dec 9, 1 page, ALS
  Informing him of the impeding arrival of the six water colors and requesting his acknowledgement of receipt and their value of $1500
- Henry Miller, Pacific Palisades, California, to William H. Runge, University of Virginia Library 1965 Dec 28, 2 pages on 1 l., ALS
  Requesting the acknowledgement of valuation prior to the last day of the year, and asking for the return of any water colors not suitable
- Henry Miller's assistant, Marcia Pessis, to William H. Runge 1964 Sep 4, 1 page, TLS
  Informing him that a copy of "Into the Night Life" and a few water colors will be arriving shortly, and explaining that because of Miller's friendship with Lawrence Clark Powell he gives his literary material to the U.C.L.A. Library
- Henry Miller's assistant, Connie Shepard, to William H. Runge 1965 Dec 1, 1 page, TLS
  Sending word of the water colors being sent and that Miller needs acknowledgement and evaluation of them as soon as possible
- Henry Miller's assistant, Connie Shepard, to William H. Runge 1966 Apr 9, 1 page, TLS
  Requesting for Miller color slides or transparencies of the water colors previously sent to the Library, and explaining the best way to take photographs of the water colors
- William H. Runge to Henry Miller's assistant, Marcia Pessis 1964 Sep 9, 1 page, TL (carbon)
  Acknowledging her letter of September 4th, and commenting on Miller's archive going to the U.C.L.A. Library
- William H. Runge to Henry Miller 1964 Sep 25, 1 page, TL (carbon)
  Acknowledging receipt of "Into the Night Life" and commenting on its being beautifully done and looking forward to the arrival of the water colors
- William H. Runge to Henry Miller 1965 Nov 8, 1 page, TL (carbon)
  Writing that the Library would be delighted to accept the water colors
- William H. Runge to Henry Miller 1965 Dec 30, 1 page, TL (carbon)
  Acknowledging receipt of the water colors and their value of $1500 as reported to the University's Rector and Visitors